<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description>Documentation for Gestalt</description>
        <link>/</link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 11:04:25 -0700</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 11:04:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
        
        <item>
            <title>Visualization Update</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It will be useful to show groupings of affected regions as part of the 
contagion storyline, so we have implemented to dynamically do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image will be updated shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <link>/20160727_update_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">/20160727_update_1.html</guid>
            
            <category>updates</category>
            
            <category>visualizations</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Reading Group Update</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, we will be reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computer.org/csdl/trans/tg/preprint/07192646.pdf&quot;&gt;Beyond Memorability: Visualization Recognition and Recall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shorten our reading from two papers to one so that we can focus more time on completing the project.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <link>/20160727_update_2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">/20160727_update_2.html</guid>
            
            <category>updates</category>
            
            <category>reading_group</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Database Update</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;We understand the importance of structuring the database. For this reason, 
we are happy to bring you the script to build the database’s tables. These 
tables contain the data necessary for the layout of the UI. You can view 
them under &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gestalt/external/database&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, we would like to script the entire setup because we want it 
to be  an install-and-play for those who are interested. But for now, please 
enjoy the script to build the database’s tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we have improved the backend for the desktop prototype. It extracts
the data from the PostgreSQL database.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <link>/20160726_update.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">/20160726_update.html</guid>
            
            <category>updates</category>
            
            <category>database</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Visualization Update</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Gestalt is in the process of building multiple different visualizations
for the contagion dataset. For those of you who are not familiar with 
what a contagion dataset represents, think of the game Pandemic and 
the likelihood of a certain event occuring based on a previous event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will approach this in a variety of ways. In a contagion dataset, you 
want to determine the &lt;strong&gt;high degree nodes&lt;/strong&gt; (or the nodes with the highest
number of connections). The reason why we want to know the high degree
node is because it has the highest influence to be contagious. We will 
visualize this via a &lt;em&gt;tile grid map&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;horizontal bar graph&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect that we would like to extract from a contagion dataset
is &lt;strong&gt;directionality&lt;/strong&gt;. We will visualize this via a &lt;em&gt;line graph&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, what are the probability that a particular node will be 
affected by the contagion? We will visualize &lt;strong&gt;contingent probability
of a crisis&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;em&gt;lollipop graph&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you look forward to our future updates as much as we do. 
We really can’t wait to see the result!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <link>/20160725_update.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">/20160725_update.html</guid>
            
            <category>updates</category>
            
            <category>visualizations</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Desktop Prototype Update</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;We are in the process of revising the desktop prototype. This development is 
currently being implemented in a separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tiffanyj41/adp&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;.
It will be integrated to the Gestalt repo after its completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future build will utilize Angular 1.0 as the frontend and Django as the backend. 
The reason why we decided to pursue Django and forego webpy is because Django has
more features than webpy’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are going to ingest large numbers of data, processing these data will 
consume a lot of time. For this reason, we need additional backend besides Django to 
run our tasks asynchronously because Django cannot run very long processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hope is that we can integrate Celery with Django since Celery is meant to handle
asynchronous tasks. We will then connect Celery to Spark to process the big data.
The data will then be fed from PostgreSQL database. This database will still reside
in the OpenStack Server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;docimage&quot; src=&quot;images/20160721.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;adp&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <link>/20160721_update.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">/20160721_update.html</guid>
            
            <category>updates</category>
            
            <category>prototypes</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
